James Pritts

Web-page · Scholar · Github · Linkedin

□ jbpritts@fb.com **□** +1 512 650 8293

Research Interests

My research is on robust multi-model estimation and minimal solvers with applications to geometric camera auto-calibration, scene-plane rectification and modeling repeated scene content. The goal of future work is to extend these methods to applications in visual localization and feature matching.

Education

Czech Technical University, Prague, Czechia PhD candidate, Computer Science (defending Sep. 15, 2020) Thesis: "Methods for the Rectification of Imaged Coplanar Repeated Patterns"	2020
Czech Technical University, Prague, Czechia MSc, Computer Science, with honors	2013
The University of North Texas, Denton, TX	2002

Experience

BSc, Mathematics

P-1-1-1-1-1	
Facebook Reality Labs, AR/VR, Pittsburgh PA	2019 - Now
Post-Doctoral Research Scientist Responsible for developing methods for the geometric calibration and auto-calibration	
of head-mounted capture systems.	
BAE Systems, Advanced Information Technologies, Burlington, MA	2003 - 2008
Lead Software Engineer	

Led teams to develop state-of-the-art computer-vision based defense systems. Managed relations with government customers and contractors by serving as the point of contact. Conducted successful program demos and reviews.

NASA, Johnson Space Center, Houston, TX Researcher Developed new body tracking technology for the purpose of remotely controlling the robotic arm of the International Space Station.

Publications

- Y. Lochman, O. Dobosevych, R. Hryniv, and J. Pritts. Minimal Solvers for Single-View Auto-Calibration. In WACV (accepted), 2021
- **J. Pritts**, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, Y. Lochman, and O. Chum. Minimal Solvers for Rectifying from Radially-Distorted Conjugate Translations. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence*, 2020
- **J. Pritts**, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, Y. Lochman, and O. Chum. Minimal Solvers for Rectifying from Radially-Distorted Scales and Change of Scales. *International Journal of Computer Vision*, 128(4):950–968, 2020
- J. Pritts, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, and O. Chum. Rectification from Radially-Distorted Scales. In ACCV, 2018
- **J. Pritts**, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, and O. Chum. Radially-Distorted Conjugate Translations. In *CVPR*, 2018
- **J. Pritts**, D. Rozumnyi, M. P. Kumar, and O. Chum. Coplanar Repeats by Energy Minimization. In BMVC, 2016

- J. Pritts, O. Chum, and J. Matas. Detection, Rectification and Segmentation of Coplanar Repeated Patterns. In CVPR, 2014
- J. Pritts, O. Chum, and J. Matas. Approximate Models for Fast and Accurate Epipolar Geometry Estimation. In *IVCNZ*, 2013

Awards

Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) Saburo Tsuji Best Paper Award for "Rectification from Radially-Distorted Scales"	2018
Computer Vision Winter Workshop (CVWW) Best Presentation Award for "Detection, Rectification, and Segmentation of Coplanar Repeated Patterns"	2014
Image and Vision Computing New Zealand (IVCVNZ) Best Paper Award for "Approximate Models for Fast and Accurate Epipolar Geometry Estimation"	2013
Dean's Prize for Outstanding Master's Thesis, CTU in Prague	2013

Supervision

Yaroslava Lochman	Thesis: "Minimal Solvers for Single-View Auto-Calibration" (after 12/2020 will pursue a PhD at Chalmers University of Technology)	2018 - Now
B.Sc. Students:	<i>Ogg/</i>	
Kostiantyn Liepieshov	Thesis: "Manhattan Frame Detection in Lens Distorted Images"	2019 – Now
	(now a M.Sc. student at Ukrainian Catholic University)	

Academic Activities

Reviewer for ECCV, 3DV

Teaching

Image Retrieval Instructor - Master's level, Ukrainian Catholic University	2017 - 2018
Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning, AE4B33RPZ TA - Bachelor's level, Czech Technical University in Prague	2013 - 2016

Invit

ited Talks	
Opportunities and Risks of Artificial Intelligence The Aspen Institute's 2018 Young Leader's Program, Tále, Slovakia	03/2018
Radially-Distorted Conjugate Translations Ukrainian Catholic University Data Science Colloquium, Lviv, Ukraine	12/2017
Detection, Rectification, and Segmentation of Coplanar Repeated Patterns The Eastern European Computer Vision Conference, Odessa, Ukraine	07/2017
Visual Recognition in the Wild: Image Retrieval, Faces, and Text The Eastern European Computer Vision Conference, Odessa, Ukraine	07/2016
Detection, Rectification and Segmentation of Coplanar Repeated Patterns The 34th Pattern Recognition and Computer Vision Colloquium, Prague, Czechia	04/2014

Programming Skills

Matlab, C/C++, Python, I₄TEX